Encounters are mysterious! But cases are even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والقضايا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is the mansion solution! There's more than just a code here!
!اليوم ختام قضيّة القصر! لا يتوقّف الأمر على الشفرة
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The old guy received a letter from someone named Nakamura Misao,
تلقّى العمّ رسالةً من شخص يُدعى ناكامورا ميساو
asking him to solve the strange mysteries of an inherited mansion.
تطلب منه حلّ ألغاز غريبة في قصرٍ موروث
The mansion really was full of mysteries.
كان القصر يعجّ بالألغاز حقّاً
One handrail post by the front door had a tiger sculpture on it.
كان أحد عامودَي السور أمام المدخل يحوي فوقه مجسّم نمر
The other post had strange holes in it.
بينما بالآخر فتحة غريبة
The house was filled with clocks.
كان المنزل مليئاً بالساعات
One clock had had something removed from it.
وإحداها قد نُزع منها ما يبدو أنّه كان ملتصقاً بها
At exactly 11:00, all the digital clocks in the house rang.
عند تمام الحادية عشرة، رنّت كلّ الساعات الرقمية في المنزل
The VCR's timer was set for exactly one minute.
كان مؤقّت جهاز الفيديو مضبوطاً لدقيقة تماماً
All the digital clocks had a crack in the same spot.
احتوت كلّ الساعات الرقمية خدشاً في الموضع نفسه
It all seems to have been set up to convey something.
بدا أنّها تحاول الإيحاء بشيء
What's more, someone seemed to be hiding in the attic!
فوق ذلك، هناك شخص يُشتبه !باختبائه في العليّة
File 'Goblin'
وكان يوجد ملفّ في المكتب يحوي مقالات صحف
about the Goblins, a bandit gang that had disappeared ten years ago.
عن الأغوال، عصابة لصوص اختفت قبل 10 أعوام
Demon, the name of the Goblins' leader, was found on a golf bag.
،وجدنا اسم مماثلاً لاسم زعيمهم، ديمون على حقيبة غولف أيضاً
Even stranger was the mirror affixed to the desk
فوق ذلك، ما أثار الغرابة أكثر هو المرآة المثبّتة على الحائط
and the hole in the wall directly below the cuckoo clock!
والفتحة في الحائط أسفل ساعة الوقواق تماماً
And what came out of the cuckoo clock at 1:10...
وما خرج من ساعة الوقواق ...عند الواحدة وعشر دقائق
...were ghastly goblin figures!
!كان مجسّمات أغوال شيطانيّة مرعبة
Where is the key to solving these mysteries?!
أين مفتاح حلّ هذه الألغاز؟
Demon figures from the cuckoo clock...
...مجسّمات شياطين من ساعة الوقواق
Demons aren't animals!
!الشياطين ليست حيوانات
What are such creepy things doing there?
لمَ توجد تلك الأشياء المريبة هنا؟
Those aren't just demons.
إنّها ليست مجرّد شياطين
They're definitely the goblin figures
بل نفس مجسّمات الأغوال التي كانت
the Bandits of the Wind used to leave behind!
عصابة الريح تتركها وراءها بلا شكّ
But why three of them?!
لكن لمَ ثلاثة منها؟
Oh, that's it! That's the weird thing I saw the other day!
هذا هو! إنّه الشيء الغريب !الذي رأيته ذاك اليوم
What?
ماذا؟
L-Look!
!ا-انظروا
There are letters on each of their heads!
!توجد أحرف على رؤوسهم
Oh! What are these?!
بالفعل! ما هذه؟
The far right demon has "R"...
...حرف "آر" على الشيطان الأيمن
The middle one has "N"...
...و"إن" على الشيطان الأوسط
And the left demon has "L"...
...و"إل" على الشيطان الأيسر
If the "L" and "R" mean "left" and "right,"
إذا كانت "آر" و"إل" تشيران ...لليمين واليسار بالإنجليزية
what does the "N" in the middle mean?
فما المقصود بـ "إن" في المنتصف؟
North?
نورث؟ أي الشمال؟
It stopped.
توقّفت
When did those demons start crying out?!
متى بدأت تلك الشياطين بالعويل؟
At exactly 1:10.
عند الواحدة وعشر دقائق
1:10... That's another "110"...
...الواحدة وعشر دقائق... ما يعني "110" أخرى
But it's strange.
لكن هذا غريب
When I saw those earlier, it was at 10:50!
عندما رأيتها قبلاً، كانت قد بدأت !العويل عند العاشرة وخمسين دقيقة
Not 1:10, but 10:50?
،ليس الواحدة وعشر دقائق بل العاشرة وخمسين؟
Does that mean--
...ما يعني
Hey! Don't tell me those figures were...
...ا-اسمع، أيمكن أن تلك المجسمّات
Those figures?!
هي تلك نفسها؟
What did you say?
أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
Oh, nothing!
كلا، لا شيء
Ah.
فهمت
Now I see what's going on here!
!اكتشفتُ معظم ما يجري هنا
But I still can't figure out
لكنّي لم أجد المعنى بعد
what these strange signs and tricks Monjiro-san left behind mean!
وراء هذه الآثار الغريبة والحيل !التي تركها مونجيرو-سان في المنزل
The digital clocks and VCR all went off at 11:00...
بدأت الساعات الرقميّة وجهاز الفيديو ...بالرنين عند الحادية عشرة
The significant marks on all of the digital clocks' panels...
العلامات البارزة الموجودة في نفس الموضع على شريط كلّ الساعات
The cuckoo clock that suddenly went off at 1:10...
وساعة الوقواق التي أطلقت عويلها ...عند الواحدة وعشر دقائق
And the three goblins that came out of the clock...
،والشياطين الثلاثة الذين ظهروا من الساعة
...and the L, N, and R that were engraved on their foreheads...
وأحرف "إل" و"إن" و"آر" المحفورة على جباهها
What is the key to answering all these mysteries?
ما هو مفتاح حلّ هذه الألغاز؟
That's it!
!فهمت
What's what?
ما الأمر؟
Didn't you notice it while looking for animals around the house?
ألم تلحظ أثناء البحث عن الحيوانات في المنزل؟
I thought something was missing!
!اعتقدتُ أنّ هناك شيئاً ناقصاً
A lion!
!الأسد
I didn't see any at all! They should be really easy to design, too!
لم يكن هناك أيّ واحد، رغم أنّه !سهل التصميم وفقما يفترض
Don't be stupid! There were two big lions on the front door!
يا حمقاء، كان هنالك أسدين كبيرين !أمام المدخل
Oh? There were?
ماذا؟ حقّاً؟
Seriously, if he collected all these animals, he wouldn't forget lions.
،كما إذا جمع هذا العدد من الحيوانات فيستحيل أن يتجاهل الأسد
The lion is the king of the animals!
فهو ملك الحيوانات
King?
ملك؟
What's going on?
ما الأمر؟
What is it, Conan-kun?
ما الخطب يا كونان-كن؟
Nothing! I just remembered something funny!
!لا شيء، تذكّرتُ أمراً طريفاً فقط
Weird kid.
صبيّ غريب الأطوار
If I'm right, it's truly a unique code!
!إذا أصاب استنتاجي، فهي شفرة فريدة بحقّ
But, wait.
،لكن انتظر
If so, the letter O or the number 0 should've come out of the clock!
"إذا صحّ الأمر، فيُفترض أن يظهر حرف "أو أو رقم صفر من ساعة الوقواق
But L, N, and R came out.
،"لكن ما خرج كانت "إل" و"إن" و"آر هذه الأحرف الثلاثة
Could the cuckoo clock's code be separate from the digital clocks'?
أيمكن أنّ معنى شفرة ساعة الوقواق مختلف تماماً عن الساعة الرقمية؟
If so...
...في تلك الحالة
1:10... 110...
...الواحدة وعشر دقائق... 110
The L, N, and R on their heads...
...أحرف "إل" و"إن" و"آر" على رؤوسهم
A trio of goblins...
...ثلاثة أغوال
Trio... Three...
...ثلاثة... ثلاثيّ
Triplets... Triplets?
توأم ثلاثيّ... توأم ثلاثيّ؟
The L, N, and R are triplets!
!إل" و"إن" و"آر" توأم ثلاثيّ"
Wait a minute!
!انتظر
Could it be?!
...أيمكن
Ah! I've got it completely figured out!
!فهمت، اكتشفت كلّ شيء
Conan-kun? Where are you?
كونان-كن! أين أنت؟
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Sheesh! Where did you go?
أين ذهبت؟
Where's your dad?
أين العمّ؟
In the study, still figuring out the code.
لا يزال يفكّر بالشفرة في المكتب
At this rate, it's going to get dark soon.
على هذا النحو، سيخيم الظلام قريباً
Rushing won't help.
الاستعجال لن يفيد بشيء
But...
...لكن
The answer might come if we think hard into the night!
قد تأتي الإجابة إذا فكّرنا ملياً طوال اللّيل
I can't figure it out.
لا أستطيع اكتشافها
The digital clocks all went off at 11:00 a.m.
رنّت كلّ الساعات الرقمية ...عند الحادية عشرة صباحاً
There's a crack on all the digital panels after the digits "110"...
وتوجد خدوش على كل شاشاتها ...بعد رقم 110
And the cuckoo clock rang at 1:10. Another "110."
،ورنّت ساعة الوقواق عند الواحدة وعشر دقائق أي "110" أخرى
They're all 110!
!كلّها 110
What does 110 mean?!
!ما معنى 110؟
Is it the emergency police number after all?
أهو رقم الشرطة فحسب بالفعل؟
Hey. Maybe it's time we give up and go home?
ربما حان وقت الاستسلام والعودة للبيت
But it's strange.
لكن هذا غريب
It would've made more sense to set the digital clocks to 1:10, too.
كان سيكون ضبط الساعات الرقمية على ...الواحدة وعشر دقائق أيضاً أكثر منطقيّة
Hey, Dad.
...اسمع يا أبي
Dad! Earth to Dad!
...أبي
Shut up! If you wanna go home, then go home!
...أبي! أنا
Don't get mad at me!
!لا تغضب عليّ
I guess it's late enough now.
اقترب الوقت
110... 110... 11...
...واحد واحد صفر... واحد واحد صفر ...واحد واحد
That's it! Stripes!
!فهمت! التخطيط
"11" refers to a striped pattern!
!تشير 11 إلى نمط التخطيط
So if we check all the zebras in the house, we'll find something!
لذا إذا تفقّدنا كلّ الحمير الوحشيّة !في المنزل فسنجد شيئاً بالتأكيد
But wouldn't he have chosen 11:11 instead?
لكن ألم يكن عليه اختيار 11:11 في تلك الحالة؟
Plus, tigers have stripes, too.
كما أن النمور مخطّطة أيضاً
Yeah. There are striped cats, too...
...صحيح، توجد قطط مخطّطة كذلك
Say, which are stronger, zebras or tigers?
بالمناسبة، ما الأقوى بين الحمير الوحشيّة والنمور؟
Eh? Tigers, right?
ماذا؟ النمور، أليس كذلك؟
Then tigers are the ♪1 animal?
النمور هي رقم 1 بين الحيوانات إذاً؟
Oh! Lions are?
!صحيح! الأسود
No wonder they're called "king of all sixty beasts"!
!كما يُتوقع من ما يُسمّى بملك الستّين وحشاً
Sixty?
الستّين؟
You're dumb. They're "king of all 100 beasts."
يا أحمق، تقصد ملك المئة وحش
[In Japanese, "100 beasts" sounds like "110,"] King of 100 beasts?!
ملك المئة وحش؟
[and "king" sounds like the letter "O."] Eh? King of 110?
(ماذا؟ ملك المئة وحش؟ (110 + أو
King of all 100 Beasts' [110 + O]
ملك المئة وحش
That's it! I've figured it out!
!هكذا إذاً! حللتُها
This "1100" is a code referring to the king of all the beasts: the lion!
شفرة "1100" هذه تشير لملك !المئة وحش، أي ملك الوحوش: الأسد
The mark between the zeroes
الخدش بين الصفرين كان يلمّح
was trying to tell us to think of them as separate words!
!للتفكير بهما منفصلين
Checking the lions will solve this mystery!
!تفقّد الأسود سيحلّ اللغز
B-But I don't see any lions...
لـ-لكنّي لا أرى أيّة أسود
Monjiro-san probably got rid of all unrelated lions in the house
لا بدّ أنّ مونجيرو-سان تخلّص من كلّ الأسود غير المرتبطة في المنزل
to keep them from distracting us!
!كيلا تشتّت انتباهنا
So that's why some things seemed broken or scraped away!
لذا بدا أنّ هنالك أشياءً !محطّمة أو تمّ نزعها
Yup!
!أجل
Then are the lions in question the ones on the front door?!
هل الأسد المقصود هو الذي أمام المدخل إذاً؟
Yes! We should find something if we check them out!
!أجل، سنجد شيئاً بالتأكيد إذا تفقدّناه
Nothing seems strange about them.
لا شيء غريب به
It would seem not.
ذلك ما يبدو
Besides, how do you explain that cuckoo clock?
كما كيف تفسّر ساعة الوقواق؟
"King" in Japanese starts with the letter "O."
إذا كان المقصود هو ملك المئة الوحش، فيُفترض أنّ حرف "أو" الذي يعني "ملك" قد ظهر
T-True. "LNR" doesn't fit with the "king" thing.
"مـ-معك حقّ، لا تتوافق "إل إن آر" مع "ملك
Could it have meant something else?
أيمكن أنّ لها معنى مختلفاً؟
That only appeared in the cuckoo clock.
فقد ظهرت في ساعة الوقواق فقط
It isn't out of the question...
...ليس مستبعداً
...but then what? Is there yet another way to read 110?
لكن ماذا إذاً؟ أهناك طريقة أخرى لقراءة 110؟
It's 1:10, so if you split the 1 and 10...
إنّها الواحدة وعشر دقائق، فإذا ...فصلت 1 و10
One, "i," ten, "to"...
..."واحد، "آي"، 10، "تو
One, ten... One, "to"... "Hi," "to"...
،"واحد، "تين"، واحد، "تو" ..."هي"، "تو"
Hitou? [secluded hot spring]
(هيتو (ينبوع ساخن معزول
Hitou
هيتو
Ito
(إيتو (خيط
Ito? [thread]
إيتو
Itou
(إيتوو (اسم شخص
ltou? [person's name]
إيتوو؟
Yeah, Itou!
!أجل، إيتوو
Did Monjiro-san know anyone named "Itou-san"?!
أخبراني، هل كان يملك مونجيرو-سان أحداً بين معارفه يُدعى إيتوو-سان؟
I don't know...
...لا أدري
Then how about a Naitou-san or a Saitou-san?!
ماذا عن نايتو-سان أو سايتو-سان إذاً؟
What's so funny?!
ما المضحك؟
It's neat! Changing the first letter makes completely different names!
هذا طريف! فتغيير الحرف الأوّل !يقلب الاسم تماماً
What's so neat about that?!
ما الطريف في ذلك؟
Come to think of it, those goblins had letters on their heads.
بالمناسبة، كان على كلّ رؤوس تلك الأغوال أحرف
They all looked the same, too.
بدت متطابقةً أيضاً
The L, N, and R on their heads... And they looked the same?
إل" و"إن" و"آر" على رؤوسها... ومتطابقة
Three similar words that start with L, N, and R, followed by 110?
"ثلاث كلمات متشابهة تبدأ بـ "إل و"إن" و"آر"، ثمّ 110؟
Yes!
!فهمت
That's it!
!هذه هي
The cuckoo clock code was saying to put L, N, and R before "ight"!
كانت شفرة ساعة الوقواق تلك عن ثلاث كلمات ،"تبدأ بأحرف "إن" و"إل" و"آر
It was saying, "Light! Night! Right!"
ضوء، ليل، يمين
Something will happen if we shine a light on the right lion at night!
أي أنّه سيحصل شيء إذا سلّطنا نوراً !على الأسد الأيمن ليلاً
Amazing, Dad!
!مذهل يا أبي
But you just shone light on it.
لكنّك فعلت ذلك قبل قليل
Yeah, huh?
...صحيح
Huh? What could that be?
ماذا؟ ما هذا يا ترى؟
See? Right behind the right lion!
انظروا، وراء الأسد الأيمن
What now?
ماذا؟
It's not very obvious, but it looks like it opens up.
،ليس واضحاً إذا لم تمعن النظر لكن يبدو أنّه يُفتح
It does!
!بالفعل
I see! If you shine the light through here--
...فهمت! إذا سلّطت النور عبر هذه الفتحة
Huh?
ماذا؟
T-This is--
...هـ-هذا
Hey, Ran. Close the door and shine the light through here.
ران! أغلقي الباب وأبقي النور !مسلّطاً عبر الفتحة
Right!
!حسناً
The light is reflecting!
!الضوء ينعكس
Oh! There's a mirror in the post!
!فهمت! توجد مرآة في العامود
Let's just follow the light!
!بأيّ حال، لنتبع النور فحسب
It goes inside the mansion through a hole in the wall!
!إنّه يدخل القصر عبر فتحة في الحائط
That's the hole in the study!
!إنّها الفتحة التي كانت في المكتب
Alright! To the study!
!حسنٌ، لنتوجّه للمكتب
Did you find anything?!
أوجدتم شيئاً؟
Just keep shining the light with the door closed!
!واصلي تسليط النور مع إغلاق الباب فحسب
Eh? Still?
ماذا؟ ليس بعد؟
What's that sound?
ما هذا الصوت؟
It's a bird this time!
!إ-إنّها حمامة وليس شيطاناً هذه المرّة
Ah!
فهمت
The light from outside reflects off the mirror on the desk
،انعكس الضوء الداخل على المرآة فوق المكتب
and shines on the cuckoo clock from below.
وأنار ساعة الوقواق من الأسفل
Is there a photometer inside?
أيوجد مقياس ضوئي في الداخل
Photometer = light detector
مقياس ضوئي
It must be set up to only work at night, so the sun won't set it off.
لا بدّ أنّها معدّة بحيث تعمل ليلاً فقط فلا تتأثّر بأشعّة الشمس
There's something on the bird...
يوجد شيءٌ على الحمامة
A wristwatch?
ساعة معصم؟
It sure is fancy, though! It's covered with gems!
!لكنّها فاخرة حقّاً، المجوهرات ترصّعها
If these are premium jewels, it could be worth billions of yen!
إذا كانت هذه جواهر ممتازة، فقد يساوي !ثمنها مليارات الينّات
Of course! After all...
...بالطبع! فهي
...it's probably a stolen item that Demon, the leader of the Goblins,
،سلعة مسروقة احتفظ بها ديمون ،زعيم عصابة الأغوال
secretly held on to!
!وأخفاها غالباً
Demon, the leader of the Goblins?
ديمون، زعيم عصابة الأغوال؟
The person who lived here: Monjiro-san!
الشخص الذي كان يعيش هنا، مونجيرو-سان
The figures that came out of the cuckoo clock
المجسمّات التي خرجت من ساعة الوقواق
looked just like the goblin figures the bandit gang always left behind,
بدت كمجسمّات الأغوال التي كانت عصابة اللصوص تتركها وراءها دوماً
and it looks like he received a golf bag with the alias "Demon" on it!
وبدا أنّه تلقّى حقيبة غولف !بلقبه "ديمون" عليها أيضاً
And I don't think either of them are the Misao-san who sent the letter.
كما أنّي لا أعتقد أنّ ميساو-سان الذي أرسل الرسالة لك هو أحدهما
After all, the letter said this:
:فقد كان مذكوراً في الرسالة
"I haven't been here long and don't know the house well.
لم أقض وقتاً طويلاً هنا" ولا أعرف تفاصيل المنزل
I figured I wouldn't discover anything on my own."
"رأيتُ أنّي لن أكتشف شيئاً من تلقاء نفسي
Yet, they knew how to open the old door, and they live here together.
،لكنّهما عرفا كيف يفتحان الباب العتيق ويعيشان هنا معاً
Plus, he thought the cuckoo came out at 10:50 instead of 1:10.
كما أنّه أخطأ باعتقاد أنّ ساعة الوقواق رنّت عند العاشرة والخمسين بدل الواحدة وعشر دقائق
This is because he didn't see the clock directly.
والسبب هو عدم رؤيته مباشرةً للساعة
Instead, he looked through the hole and saw the clock in the mirror!
بل اختلس النظر عبر الفتحة في الحائط !ورأى صورة الساعة في المرآة
In short, when Misao-san mentioned being watched by someone...
...أي أنّ الشخص الذي شكّ ميساو-سان بمراقبته له
...that was referring to these two!
!هو هما
Besides, I think Misao-san is a woman.
كما أنّي أعتقد أنّ ميساو-سان امرأة
What?
ماذا؟
Here! Look at the stamp on this letter!
انظر للطابع على هذه الرسالة
See the lipstick on the underside?
يوجد أحمر شفاه أسفله، أليس كذلك؟
Oh! She licked it when sticking it on here...
!فهمت! لعقتْه عندما لصقته هنا
But I'm sure you had this all figured out already!
لكنّي متأكّد أنّك اكتشفت !كلّ ذلك سلفاً يا عمّ
Oh, uhh, yeah...
...أجل
So, does that mean--?!
...ما يعني، أنتما
Impressive.
مُبهر
We're the remnants of the Goblins.
نحن أعضاء باقون للأغوال
We came to get the last treasure our boss had held on to.
أتينا لأخذ الكنز الأخير الذي تمسّك الزعيم به
Held on to?
تمسّك به؟
Yeah, when we disbanded, he gave us almost everything we stole,
أجل، عندما انفصلنا، قام بمنحنا معظم ما سرقناه
but he kept the most valuable items all for himself.
!لكنّه احتفظ بأثمن الغنائم، واستأثرها لنفسه
And those would be the jewels on this watch?
وتلك هي الجواهر على هذه الساعة؟
He finally kicked the bucket, so we decided to scour this house
مات أخيراً، فأتينا لتفتيش هذا المنزل الذي
he used to hole up in... but there was someone already here.
كان يستعمله كمخبأ... لكنّنا وجدنا شخصاً
I assume it was the real Misao-san, who's locked in the attic now?
وهي ميساو-سان الحقيقيّة المحتجزة في العليّة حالياً، صحيح؟
Yeah. When we tossed her up there, she just kept wailing on
أجل، واصلت الصراخ عندما احتجزناها هناك
about how some great detective would be here soon to get us.
وقالت أنّ متحرّياً عظيماً على وشك القدوم هنا، فعلينا التحضّر
And then you showed up at the perfect time,
ثمّ أتيتَ في الوقت المناسب
so I pretended to be her to have you solve the code our boss left.
فانتحلتُ هويّتها كي أجعلك تحلّ الشفرة التي تركها الزعيم
Now hand over the watch.
!هيّا، فلتسلّم الساعة
Hand it over quietly and I won't kill you.
سلّمها بطواعيّة ولن أقتلك
Here you go.
هاك
B-Bastard!
!الـ-الوغد
What was that just now?
لحظة، ما كان ذلك؟
Don't move! Move and I snap her neck!
!لا تتحرّك! افعل وسأكسر عنقها
You idiot!
!أ-أحمق
Don't do that!
!توقّف
A-A heel drop...
...ضـ-ضربة كاحل سفلية
That scared me!
!أفزعني
It did?
حقّاً؟
Alright! Let's contact the police!
!حسنٌ! لنتّصل بالشرطة
After we contacted them, the local police rushed to the scene.
بعد اتّصالنا، أتت الشرطة المحليّة للمكان فوراً
Still knocked out, the criminal duo was carried into ambulances,
نُقل المجرمان فاقدي الوعي للإسعاف كما هما
and Misao-san was rescued from the attic, safe and sound.
وأُنقذت ميساو-سان من العليّة بسلام
Just as I thought, she was the girl in the photo with Monjiro-san.
كما توقّعنا، كانت الفتاة في الصورة مع مونجيرو-سان
I see.
هكذا إذاً؟
So this was in the cuckoo clock?
كانت هذه داخل ساعة الوقواق؟
Monjiro-san probably made the watch for you out of stolen jewels.
صنع مونجيرو-سان هذه الساعة لك من الجواهر المسروقة غالباً
Nobody will know about it if you don't say anything...
قد لن يكتشف أحدٌ أمرك ...إذا أخذتِها سرّاً
But stolen goods are stolen goods. I can't accept it.
،لكن تبقى الأغراض المسروقة مسروقةً لا يمكنني قبولها
Besides, my grandfather has already given me
كما أنّ جدّي قد أعطاني شيئاً
something more valuable than jewels.
أكثر قيمة من الجواهر
The mysteries scattered about this mansion.
الألغاز المتناثرة في هذا القصر
For a mystery writer like me, it's the greatest present!
!بالنسبة لمؤلّفة غموض مثلي، هذه أفضل هديّة
Oh...
...فهمت
Still, it's a waste...
...لكن، سيكون هذا إهداراً
It's all right.
لا بأس
Who knows, maybe it was actually meant for whoever found it!
ربما كانت هذه الساعة لأيّ !من يجدها، وليس لي تحديداً
Then it's for me?!
!في تلك الحالة، لي أنا؟
Dad!
!أبي
I don't think so, old guy.
ليس صحيحاً يا عمّ
That was most definitely a watch Monjiro-san made for Misao-san.
فهذه الساعة من صنع مونجيرو-سان لميساو-سان بلا شكّ
Look closely at the watch face.
أمعن النظر لعقارب الساعة
It's stopped at 3:30. 330 can be read as "Misao."
"توقّفت عند الثالثة والنصف. 330 تُقرأ "ميساو
Nakai-san!
!ناكاي-سان
That's--!
...هذا
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Express bus.
حافلة طريق سريع
Next episode's case is about a scoop.
قضيّة الحلقة القادمة !سبق صحفيّ
Who's that person next to you in the photo, dad?
من هذا الظاهر في الصورة مع أبي؟
Crap!
!تبّاً